this is the new best way to remove
background noise in final cut pro first
thing you want to do is select your clip
and once you get that selected in the
upper right hand corner we are going to
go to this audio symbol this is the
audio inspector and inside here the old
way of doing this was just to use the
noise removal but this thing was
absolutely terrible it did not work so
well now final cut pro actually just
came out with a brand new tool and it's
called voice isolation and honestly this
thing i think it might be magic this
tool is perfect for removing background
noise whether you have an air
conditioner in the background or you
have some hiss white noise static or
even just loud background noise in the
background of your shots so let's see
just how good this voice isolation tool
is we're gonna test it on two different
levels first we're gonna start with a
level one clip which is difficulty easy
and then we're going to jump to a level
10 clip which is difficulty hard scratch
that difficulty extremely hard so right
here is our level one clip which is
pretty easy we have an air conditioner
in the background and take a listen to
this sean was sitting right underneath
it and it was pretty loud yeah i mean
my hard goal is now this thing is pretty
loud and annoying but we're gonna see if
we can remove this air conditioner from
the shot and just isolate his voice so
we select the clip and then we're gonna
go back up here under voice isolation
and automatically it's going to set it
to 50 percent and let's play it and see
how it sounds and then from there we can
adjust in fact like that is the language
that alex hermosi and that sounds pretty
good and just for reference let me show
you what this sounds like with it turned
off in fact like that is the language
that alex hermosie and layla speak is
like the reason they do it is now like i
said this thing is like magic and it
does a really good job but we can
actually increase this a little bit if
we want to just by sliding this up to
let's try seventy percent and see how
that sounds in fact like that is the
language that alex hermosie and layla
honestly at 75 that is sounding really
really good level one complete let's
move on to level 10 difficulty extremely
hard take a listen to this and let's see
if we can make it sound any better the
your first thing to do after joining is
to watch niche finder which i know is
something to watch and we have all this
other stuff yeah that's that's going to
be pretty difficult to remove all that
background noise but stay tuned because
i do have some audio tricks inside of
final cut pro that you can do to make
this sound a lot better even after doing
the voice isolation tool so let's just
get right into it first things first
let's just go ahead and apply the voice
isolation at 50 and see how it sounds
after joining is to watch niche finder
which i know is something to watch now
it sounds pretty good but the background
noise is still bleeding through just a
little bit so i'm going to play it again
and increase the percentage no it's
something to watch and we have all this
other stuff but like there's nothing
like it so 100 is just a bit too much
but i feel like right around that 80
percent is where it sounds pretty good
without distorting the voice too much
like i said though there are a few other
tricks we want to do to this clip to
make it sound better now the first thing
we're going to do sounds a little bit
backwards or counter-intuitive but we're
actually going to add in some background
music or background sound effects the
reason we do this is because when we
remove all of that background noise it's
just him talking and he's talking really
loud and it doesn't sound quite natural
your first thing to do after joining is
to watch niche finder but if we add in
some sound effects or some music it's
going to sound a lot better i'm going to
be using epidemicsound.com and you guys
can try this too you can get a 30 day
free trial by going to
thinkmediasounds.com
and then do exactly what i'm going to do
on this video first we'll start off by
downloading a sound effect that is going
to sound natural in the background of
the video all you got to do is go to the
search bar and then we are going to type
in something like people talking and
we're going to see what pops up right
here we have a large exterior crowd
which sounds like it would be good but
let's take a listen and see if it fits
all right i love that sound effect so
we're gonna go over here to download and
just like that i can download this and
then apply it inside of final cut pro so
now i'm gonna drag the volume of the
sound effects down to about negative 12
decibels and let's hear what it sounds
like with and without the sound effects
your first thing to do after joining is
to watch niche finder which i know it's
something to watch and we have all this
other stuff but like there's nothing
like it the nice thing about removing
backer noise and then adding it in later
is it still sounds natural but you're
able to mix the volume exactly how you
want now the other thing you can do is
add in background music but there's a
trick you can do to the actual song to
make it sound a lot better when it's
paired with a human voice now back on
epidemicsound.com we are going to go to
music and one of my favorite things to
do is actually browse through the
playlist that they have they have
amazing music in these playlists makes
it really easy to find the right song
one of my favorite playlists is called
podcast hip hop and in here there is
just a bunch of really cool beats that
would work perfect to go in the
background of this clip another great
feature they have is that you can sort
through these playlists or really any of
the music by genre mood vocals duration
or bpm so i'm gonna go over to mood and
then i'm gonna select happy going with
those happy vibes and i'm gonna listen
to these and see which one i want
okay okay okay i think that's the song
we're gonna go to download and we're
gonna download that to my computer and
then just drag that right into final cut
pro so here's what we need to do with
the music to make it sound really really
good with his voice the first step is
we're just gonna quiet down the track a
little bit so we can edit it to the
voice the next step to this is to
actually select the music track and then
we're gonna go up here in the audio
inspector and we are going to mess with
the equalizer so that it's not clashing
with his voice as much and i'm gonna
keep this super simple i'm just going to
play the clip and then drag this down a
little bit in the higher ends so that
his voice is going to stand out a little
bit more after joining is to watch niche
finder which i know is something to
watch that sounds much better and the
last step which is the icing on the cake
is we want to select the actual clip
with the audio of sean talking and then
we are going to eq his voice as well
your first thing to do but like there's
nothing like it so now let's listen to
what level 10 sounds like before and
then after your first thing to do after
joining is to watch niche finder which i
know is something to watch and we have
all this other stuff but like there's
nothing like it that is much easier to
hear his voice and even with all that
background noise we made it sound a lot
better if you want to see my favorite
effects plugins and tools that i use in
final cut pro to edit these videos then
click on the screen and i will see you
guys in the next video
[Music]